<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sam Judd</title><link>https://samjudd.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Sam Judd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 15:04:57 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://samjudd.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wellspring 2: Lessons Learned and Conclusions</title><link>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring2_lessons_and_conclusions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 15:04:57 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring2_lessons_and_conclusions/</guid><description>The End of Wellspring 2 Although I quite like the idea for Wellspring 2, I ended up deciding to stop working on the project once I was ready to work on games again after a break. The main reason is that I think there is just too much scope for me to do on my own. I love the game idea and think it would be really fun to implement, but it looks like too much for just one person.</description></item><item><title>Wellspring 2: Character Design</title><link>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring2_character_design/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 15:04:02 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring2_character_design/</guid><description>Introduction Now that I’ve talked about map design in the previous post, the next thing to get to is the character design. To establish the basics, each character has some amount of health (can vary between characters) that gets depleted as they take damage from enemy characters. When they reach 0, they are out of the game for some length of time before respawning in their own base. Each character is controlled to walk with WASD and look with the mouse.</description></item><item><title>Wellspring 2: Introduction and Map Development</title><link>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring2_intro_and_map/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 15:03:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring2_intro_and_map/</guid><description>From Wellspring 1 to Wellspring 2 Basically, I moved away from Wellspring 1 to another version to make the game development easier for myself. I am only one person, and I wanted to make something I could actually finish.
One of the biggest changes I made was moving from Unity to the Godot Engine. Here’s why I did it:
I like using it. The UI and organization make sense to me, or at least more sense than Unity.</description></item><item><title>Percent Damage Potential: Game Development Writing from 2017</title><link>https://samjudd.github.io/post/percent_damage_potential/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 17:49:15 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://samjudd.github.io/post/percent_damage_potential/</guid><description>I wrote this in 2017 in response to the &amp;ldquo;Damage Rating&amp;rdquo; statistic that got released at this link. This article no longer exists and unfortunately the link doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in the Wayback Machine either. Adding this anyway as I still think this has some interesting thoughts of mine on game development. It&amp;rsquo;s phrased as a letter to Riot, though i never ended up sending it, and is unedited from the time when it was written.</description></item><item><title>Wellspring 1: My First Attempt at a Game</title><link>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 13:11:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://samjudd.github.io/post/wellspring1/</guid><description>Introduction On the advice of my brother, I decided to start writing about my work developing a game by myself. So here goes. I started working on this a long time ago, so this work goes back in time to September-ish 2019.
I have always enjoyed playing games (some would say too much) and after working in the aerospace industry for a few years I sorta decided that it is not really my life’s passion.</description></item></channel></rss>